<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>System on Neo VRAINS</title>
    <link>https://www.sdlinks.net/tags/system/</link>
    <description>Recent content in System on Neo VRAINS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.155.3</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 13:10:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.sdlinks.net/tags/system/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>进程</title>
      <link>https://www.sdlinks.net/posts/2018/process/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 13:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sdlinks.net/posts/2018/process/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The abstraction provided by the OS of a running program is something we call a process. And there are some APIs must be
included in any interface of an operating system:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;destroy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wait&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;miscellaneous control, most OS provide some kind of method to suspend a process and resume it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;status, there are usually interfaces to get some status information about a process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing that the OS must do to run a program is to load its code and any static data into memory, into the address
space of the process. Once the code and static data are loaded into memory, there are a few other things the OS needs to
do before running the process. Some memory must be allocated for the program&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;run-time stack&lt;/em&gt;, and the OS may also
allocate smoe memory for the program&amp;rsquo;s heap. Also, the os will do some other intialization tasks, particularly as related
to I/O, i.e. in Unix systems each process by default has three open file descriptors, for standard input, output and error.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Address Space</title>
      <link>https://www.sdlinks.net/posts/2018/address-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 23:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sdlinks.net/posts/2018/address-space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-address-space&#34;&gt;The Address Space&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The address space is the abstraction that OS is providing to the running program. The address space of a process contains
all of the memory state of the running program. For example, the code of the program, the stack and the heap. In the sight
of the program, it loaded into at a particular address and has a potentially very large address space, thus, we say that
the OS is &lt;em&gt;virtualizing memory&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computer System 4</title>
      <link>https://www.sdlinks.net/posts/2018/computer-system-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 19:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sdlinks.net/posts/2018/computer-system-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;linking&#34;&gt;Linking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linking is the process of collecting and combining various pieces of code and data into a single file that can be loaded
(copied) into memory and executed. Linking can be performed at compile time, when the source code is translated into
machine code; at load time, when the program is loaded into memory and executed by the &lt;em&gt;loader&lt;/em&gt;; and even at run time, by
application programs. On modern systems, linking is performed automatically by programs called &lt;em&gt;linkers&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computer System 3</title>
      <link>https://www.sdlinks.net/posts/2018/computer-system-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 23:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sdlinks.net/posts/2018/computer-system-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;optimization&#34;&gt;Optimization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing an efficient program requires several type of activities. First, we must select an appropriate set of algorithms
and data structures. Second, we must write source code that the compiler can effectively optimize to turn into efficient
executable code. A third technique for dealing with especially demanding computations is to divide a task into portions
that can be computed in parallel, on some combination of multiple cores and multiple processors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computer System 2</title>
      <link>https://www.sdlinks.net/posts/2018/computer-system-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 17:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sdlinks.net/posts/2018/computer-system-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;assembler&#34;&gt;Assembler&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computer execute machine code, sequences of bytes encoding the low-level operations that manipulate data manage memory,
read and write data on storage devices, and communicate over networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will focus on x86-64, the commonest machine language used in processor with laptop and PC, also it&amp;rsquo;s widely used in
supercomputer and lager data center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the x86-64 machine code is much different with the corresponding C code, the processor states below are everywhere:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computer System 1</title>
      <link>https://www.sdlinks.net/posts/2018/computer-system-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 23:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sdlinks.net/posts/2018/computer-system-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hardware-organization-of-a-system&#34;&gt;Hardware Organization of A System&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A typical system has those hadrware below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buses: Running throughout the system is a collection of electrical conduits called buses that carry bytes of ingormation
back and forth betweent the components. Buses are typically designed to transfer fiexed sized chunks of bytes know as words.
The number of bytes in a word is a fundamental system parameter that varies across systems. Most have word sizes of 8 bytes
(64 bits)today&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
